<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Red_Hat_Technical_Writing_Style_Guide-Release_Notes-Release_5">
	<title>Release 5</title>
	 <section id="sect-Red_Hat_Technical_Writing_Style_Guide-Release_Notes-Release_5-Release_5.1">
		<title>Release 5.1</title>
			<para>Minor update in January 2022 to address some reported issues:</para>
			<para>Accessing IBM Style online.</para>
			<para>Updated guidance for long commands.</para>
			<para>Updated guidance for referring to object names.</para>
			<para>Updated guidance for non-breaking spaces.</para>
			<para>Updated guidance for punctuation with quotation marks.</para>
			<para>The gerund verb form is no longer required in section titles.</para>
			<para>Pronouncing file or directory names that begin with special characters.</para>
			<para>Avoid "the product allows the user to do xyz".</para>
			<para>Avoid consecutive headings.</para>
			<para>Guidance to refer to UI elements and to other publication titles.</para>
			<para>Clarification that diagram labels use sentence case.</para>
			<para>New or updated usage entries: backend, IaC, number sign, on premise/on-premise, prebaked, unset.</para>

	</section>
	 <section id="sect-Red_Hat_Technical_Writing_Style_Guide-Release_Notes-Release_5-Release_5.0">
		<title>Release 5.0</title>
			<para>Major update in July 2021 to align with some recent changes in IBM Style:</para>
			<para>Sentence case is required for captions, legends, and diagram labels.</para>
			<para>Punctuation: Added sections on referring to punctuation marks and names of punctuation marks and special characters.</para>
			<para>Rename Chapter 4 to "Choosing Appropriate Language": expand scope beyond slang and jargon, to cover inclusive language; avoiding ambiguities (moved from Chapter 2 and added more categories); dates and times (AM and PM are now written in uppercase without periods); and numbers.</para>
			<para>Usage A-Z: Various additions and updates. Corrected alphabetical sorting sequence. Moved items that are not literal term entries to an earlier chapter.</para>
			<para>Minor edits so the guide itself conforms with its own advice.</para>

	</section>

</chapter>
